Arabia
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Arabia
2.1.3.1.1.1
Marist College
  Box 1491
- Arabia, 2.1.3.1.1.1
  - Arabia, 1918; 1 (Box 1491)
    - Loading the S.S. Ozarda at Suez, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 2 (Box 1491)
    - Arabian "Hindu" bathing on deck of S.S. Ozarda, 1
    - Verso: "Bathing Bert" who took a "shower" out of a bucket five times a day, to the disgust of some of the others who had never had a bath in their lives, 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 3 (Box 1491)
    - Sheep on board deck of S.S. Ozarda [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Our fellow passengers crossing the Red Sea], 1
    - Verso: The tramp steamer on which we cross the Red Sea from Africa to Arabia, 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 4 (Box 1491)
    - Scotch Highlander cooking on deck of S.S. Ozarda, 1
    - Verso: Scene on board our floating ark, the S.S. Ozarda. Scotties preparing breakfast, 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 5 (Box 1491)
    - Scottish soldier and African on board deck of S.S. Ozarda, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 6 (Box 1491)
    - Unloading horses and mules at Akaba, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 7 (Box 1491)
    - Wadi Araba, caravan, close-up, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 8 (Box 1491)
    - Camel caravan in Wadi Araba, Lowell Thomas on camel in foreground [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A camel caravan in the Wadi Arabia], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 9 (Box 1491)
    - Wadi Ithm, 1
    - Verso: It was down the barren Wadi Ithm that Lawrence and his army advanced on Akaba, 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 10 (Box 1491)
    - Bodyguard talking to Goslett, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 11 (Box 1491)
    - Emir Feisal and T. E. Lawrence holding morning audience outside in front of tents, distant view, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 12 (Box 1491)
    - Narrow street in Jedda, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 13 (Box 1491)
    - Jedda panorama from housetop, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 14 (Box 1491)
    - Eve's Tomb, Jedda [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The last resting-place of the Mother of us all], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 15 (Box 1491)
    - Large hotel, Jedda [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The Waldorf-Astoria of Arabia-including 200 rooms with accommodations for 1000 guests with all the latest Arabian conveniences excepting bath," phone, light, heat, or service], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 16 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence standing, length [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The archeologist and poet who turned soldier], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 17 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence standing on balcony in Arab robe and headdress, full figure [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The "Uncrowned King" of the Arabs on the Governor's balcony in Jerusalem], 1
    - Verso: Chase's first picture of Colonel Lawrence is probably his best. Lawrence had come out onto the balcony of his hotel, hearing there was a riot in the street below and Chase snapped him in an unguarded moment, 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 18 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence standing outdoors on a prayer rug [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence in front of his headquarters tent], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 19 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence, D. G. Hogarth, Allan Dawnay, full length, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 20 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence, D. G. Hogarth, Allan Dawnay, close-up, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 21 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in British uniform, full figure, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 22 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence on camel, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 23 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence and his bodyguard in the desert [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: "Sidi" Lawrence and his "Sons" ], 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 - 1919; 24 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence and two Syrian advisors [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence confers with Arab Nationalists leaders from Bagdad and Damascus], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 25 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence and British staff (6) in front of tent [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: T. E. Lawrence in chair surrounded by members of his British staff], 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 -1921; 26 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, ends of headdress back over shoulders, hands clasped, sword at waist, length [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: In his white robes Lawrence looked like a prophet], 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 - 1921; 27 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe squatting, full-faced, close-up, 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 - 1921; 28 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe squatting, full-faced, close-up [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Col. T. E. Lawrence], 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 - 1921; 29 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, three quarters side view, left hand on sword [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The King-maker], 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 - 1921; 30 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, three quarters front, hands behind back, headdress over shoulders, sword at waist, 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 - 1921; 31 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe, three quarters, both hands on sword, full-faced [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Colonel T. E. Lawrence, the mystery man of Arabia], 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918-1921; 32 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, three quarter view, full-faced, head cloth hanging down [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: "Shereef" Lawrence], 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918-1921; 33 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in white, three quarter side view, hands clasped over knee, 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 - 1921; 34 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in white robe with sword at waist, sitting on floor, side view, right hand on chin [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The dreamer whose dreams came true], 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918 - 1921; 35 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence in white robe with sword at waist, seated, side view, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 36 (Box 1491)
    - Colonel P. C. Joyce, second in command to T. E. Lawrence [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Colonel Joyce, Commander of the Arab "Regulars"], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 37 (Box 1491)
    - Hussein Ibn Ali, King of the Hedjaz [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: King of the Hejaz, "Commander of the Faithful," and founder of a new Arabian dynasty], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 38 (Box 1491)
    - Emir Feisal [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Emir Feisal, now King of Mesopotamia (Irak)], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 39 (Box 1491)
    - T. E. Lawrence and Emir Feisal at right conferring with Bedouin sheiks [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Feisal and Lawrence conferring with Bedouin Sheiks], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 40 (Box 1491)
    - Emir Feisal in British army truck, Lowell Thomas stands at right, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 41 (Box 1491)
    - Auda Abu Tayi, center, and two brothers [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Sheik Auda Abu Tayi, the Bedouin Robin Hood], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 42 (Box 1491)
    - Mohammed Abu Tayi, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 43 (Box 1491)
    - Emir Feisal on horse, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 44 (Box 1491)
    - Mounted Bedouins [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Bedouin "Irregulars" ready for a raid on the Turks], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 45 (Box 1491)
    - Bedouin with curls [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A brigand from Jebel Druz], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 46 (Box 1491)
    - Arab man, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 47 (Box 1491)
    - Bedouin sheik on horse [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Tallal El-Hareidhin of Tafas], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 48 (Box 1491)
    - Bedouin with curls holding rifle [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: An Arab Apollo], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 49 (Box 1491)
    - Druses from Hauran [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Druses from the Hauran], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 50 (Box 1491)
    - Akaba waterfront [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Shore-line at the head of the Gulf of Akaba], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 51 (Box 1491)
    - Women carrying fuel on shore of Akaba, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 52 (Box 1491)
    - Squatting Bedouins, close-up, with camels at Akaba, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 53 (Box 1491)
    - Mazuk, vain Bedouin on Emir Feisal's staff, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 54 (Box 1491)
    - Arab store, horse eating in foreground, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 55 (Box 1491)
    - Malud Bey and Arab cavalry leaders, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 56 (Box 1491)
    - Arab cavalry under Malud Bey [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Malud Bey and his Arab cavalry], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 57 (Box 1491)
    - Dinner party, left to right: Nuri Pasha, Auda Abu Tayi, Emir Feisal, Lowell Thomas, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 58 (Box 1491)
    - Emir Feisal and Lowell Thomas watching battle at Maan through field glasses, 1
  Box 1492
- Arabia, 2.1.3.1.1.1
  - Arabia, 1918; 1 (Box 1492)
    - Arab regular army drawn up at foot of hill, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 2 (Box 1492)
    - Three armored cars in silhouette at sunset [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Armored cars in holy Arabia], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 3 (Box 1492)
    - Armored cars and motor trucks in front of tents at Gueira, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 4 (Box 1492)
    - Arab battery in action, sunset, fighting near Damascus [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence's mountain guns in action], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 5 (Box 1492)
    - Harry Chase taking motion pictures from armored car [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Mr. Chase opening fire with his cinema camera from the turret of an armored car], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 6 (Box 1492)
    - Bedouin cavalry and British armed cars in desert, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 7 (Box 1492)
    - Squadron of armored cars in front of cliff, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 8 (Box 1492)
    - Five Bedouin horsemen, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 9 (Box 1492)
    - Mountains of Edom near Petra, Lowell Thomas's caravan in foreground [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Our caravan approaching the "Lost City" ], 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas's caravan approaching the "enchanted" red mountains of Edom in Arabia where they visited the long lost city of Petra carved out of solid rock, 1-verso
    - Note: L.T. and party approaching the enchanted mountains of Edom, mountains of red and white limestone, in the Arabian desert. Down in a pocket among these mountains are the remains of one of the most beautiful cities on earth, the Lost City of Petra, carved from the solid rock, 2
  - Arabia, 1918; 10 (Box 1492)
    - Valley twelve miles wide running toward Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 11 (Box 1492)
    - Lowell Thomas having tea at Wadi Musa, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 12 (Box 1492)
    - Temple of Urn, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 13 (Box 1492)
    - Arab sheik on horse in front of tent, Petra, 1
    - Verso: A typical Arab sheik. Every Arab looks upon himself as being just as important as every other Arab. Their form of government is one of the most democratic in the world, 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 14 (Box 1492)
    - Our kitchen tomb, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 15 (Box 1492)
    - Temple of Isis from Gorge, Arab in foreground, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 16 (Box 1492)
    - Temple of Isis (The Deir) from gorge, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 17 (Box 1492)
    - Lowell Thomas on camel under column at the Temple of Isis (The Deir), Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: We rode into the Auditorium on our camels], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 18 (Box 1492)
    - Lowell Thomas drinking in a gorge near Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The narrow defile that leads to the "Lost City" ], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 19 (Box 1492)
    - Harry Chase in front of tent, Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Chase reads the Koran while Mohammed in the background takes aim at a circling hawk], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 20 (Box 1492)
    - Side view, temples in cliffs near camp, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 21 (Box 1492)
    - Poppy, close-up, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 22 (Box 1492)
    - Lowell Thomas and Australian soldier at altar [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: We found altars and places of sacrifice on some of the mountains above Petra], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 23 (Box 1492)
    - Monolith en route to Mount Hor, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 24 (Box 1492)
    - Lowell Thomas watches as Arab play tag around the phallic monolith, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 25 (Box 1492)
    - Three-storied temple [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The "Three-storied temple" ], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 26 (Box 1492)
    - Holy Mosque summit of Mount Hor, Lowell Thomas in foreground, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 27 (Box 1492)
    - Structure of rock, Petra, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 28 (Box 1492)
    - Bedouin camp, goats' hair tents, distant, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 29 (Box 1492)
    - Two Arab men with pistols [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: "Drinkers of the milk of war" ], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 30 (Box 1492)
    - The Kaaba, Mecca, crowd, fort in distance [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The mosque of the holy Kaaba], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 31 (Box 1492)
    - The Kaaba, Mecca, close-up, 1
    - Verso: The sacred stone is in one corner of this cube-shaped building. The pilgrims come to Mecca to kiss it and thus remove their sins, 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 32 (Box 1492)
    - The Haram, sacred mosque, Mecca, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 33 (Box 1492)
    - Medina, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 34 (Box 1492)
    - Medina, part of the Mosque of the Prophet, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 35 (Box 1492)
    - Veiled woman (copy from Zwemer), 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 36 (Box 1492)
    - Mudarwa explosion, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 37 (Box 1492)
    - The Kaaba, Mecca, distant view, 1
    - Verso: The sacred mosque in Mecca. The square black building in the center is the holy Kaaba, covered over with the famous pilgrimage carpet. Imbedded in one corner of the Kaaba is the sacred stone which millions of Mohammedans come from all parts of the world to kiss, 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 38 (Box 1492)
    - Dynamited steel bridge, Hedjaz Railway, 1
    - Verso: During the war in the Land of the Arabian Nights young Lawrence blew up seventy-nine Turkish bridges. He also dynamited many trains and stations. He playfully called this "planting tulips", 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 39 (Box 1492)
    - Arab man on railway platform, full view, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 40 (Box 1492)
    - General Edmund Allenby and Emir Feisal [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Field-Marshall Viscount Allenby of Jerusalem and King Feisal of Bagdad], 1
  - Arabia, 1919; 41 (Box 1492)
    - Emir Feisal, T. E. Lawrence and group at Paris [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Emir Feisal, center, with General Nuri to the left and Colonel Lawrence to the right; Captain Pisani of the French mission standing directly behind the Emir], 1
  - Arabia, 1919; 42 (Box 1492)
    - Sunset, Red Sea, silhouette of caravan, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 43 (Box 1492)
    - Panorama of Akaba [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Panorama of Akaba], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 44 (Box 1492)
    - Panorama of a Bedouin encampment at Akaba [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A Bedouin encampment], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 45 (Box 1492)
    - Palm trees, man carrying two buckets [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Where the hosts of Israel are said to have terminated the passage of the Red Sea], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 46 (Box 1492)
    - General Jafaar Pasha from Baghdad [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: General Jafaar Pasha from Bagdad], 1
    - Verso: Mr. McFarland: Please make a dupe negative from this - but only of head + bust or down to his waist - then please send one black and white glossy print to Carnagey in that set of prints I have just asked you to make up for my book, + also one to Mr. Getz in the set you are sending him. At the same time send me 3 prints for newspaper purposes. L. T., 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 47 (Box 1492)
    - Airplane crash, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 48 (Box 1492)
    - Airplane crash, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 49 (Box 1492)
    - Armored vehicle in defile, bridge in background, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 50 (Box 1492)
    - Column of men on horseback riding down sand dunes, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 51 (Box 1492)
    - Desert encampment, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 52 (Box 1492)
    - Emir Feisal, 1
    - Verso: Emir Feisal, direct descendent of the Prophet Mohammet, who was the Arab commander-in-chief in the field. Today he is King in Baghdad, and modern successor to the Caliph Haroun al Roschid of the Arabian Nights. He was the prophet while Lawrence was the active leader and strategist., 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 53 (Box 1492)
    - King Feisal among his desert followers, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 54 (Box 1492)
    - Emir Feisal and Captain Pisani of the French Mission walking toward a tent, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 55 (Box 1492)
    - Five armed men sitting on a hillside, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 56 (Box 1492)
    - Group of people stand before unidentified tower, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 57 (Box 1492)
    - Locusts, people waving flags, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 58 (Box 1492)
    - Man kneels before unidentified tomb, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 59 (Box 1492)
    - Man sits on kneeling camel, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 60 (Box 1492)
    - Military trench, ruins of building in background, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 61 (Box 1492)
    - Colonel S. F. Newcombe, 1
  - Arabia, circa 1918; 62 (Box 1492)
    - The ruins of two buildings, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 63 (Box 1492)
    - The salt lagoon in Jezirat Faraun, Akaba, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 64 (Box 1492)
    - Auda Abu Tayi, 1
  - Arabia, undated; 65 (Box 1492)
    - Sketch of Emir Feisal by Augustus John, 1
    - Verso: H.M. King Feisal of Irak, from a portrait by Augustus John. Black and white illustration for Revolt in the Desert by" T. E. Lawrence", 1-verso
  - Arabia, 1918; 66 (Box 1492)
    - Street scene, camel at right, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 67 (Box 1492)
    - Three people and camels in the Arabian desert [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The sands of Araby], 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 68 (Box 1492)
    - Two armed men, close-up, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 69 (Box 1492)
    - Unidentified compound, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 70 (Box 1492)
    - Unidentified man holding pith helmet and cane, 1
  - Arabia, 1918; 71 (Box 1492)
    - View from airplane of military camp and unidentified city (aerial view), 1